Guide to the Larry Spruch Papers MC.209
New York University Archives
- Series VI: University of Pennsylvania Coursework, 1943-1950
  - Preliminary Examinations: University of Pennsylvania, 1945-1948 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Physics 600: Mechanics, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Physics 201, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Physics 15: Atomic and Molecular Physics, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Notes on various topics, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Physics 652: Statistical Mechanics, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Physics 510, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Physics 500, 1946-1947 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Physics 630: Quantum Mechanics, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - University of Pennsylvania thesis notes and manuscripts, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Atomic Physics, undated (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Notes on elasticity, undated (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Mixed coursework, undated (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Physics 500: Mathematical Physics problems, undated (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - "On the Beta-Decay of H3", undated (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Analytical Mechanics notes, undated (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Mechanics problems, undated (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - Physics 520, undated (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - German 1 R C: "Readings of difficult German prose for Ph.D. language examinations", undated (Box 36, Folder 32)
- Series VII: Personal Materials, 1948-2002
  Series VII contains materials related to Larry Spruch's personal life, rather than his work as a physicist. Many of the materials in this series are maps, souvenirs, and other tourist ephemera gathered by Spruch during his travels around the world. Though much of that travel was the result of Spruch's participation in the conferences, seminars, and workshops (see Series IV: Subseries C), he made time to explore the area as well. Other materials in the series are related to Spruch's personal interests, which included theatre and progressive politics. The materials in this series date from between 1948 and 2002.
  - Henry Wallace presidential campaign ephemera, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1950-1990 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Book and theater reviews, 1951-1960 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Progressive magazine, vol. 18 no. 4, 1954 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - University of Pennsylvania Department of Physics newsletter, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Florida tourism ephemera, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Theater programs, Phi Beta Kappa banquet program, and telephone directory for Physikalisches Institut, 1962, 1986, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - United Kingdom newspaper clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - United Farm Workers, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Aspen, CO travel ephemera, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Larry Spruch passport, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Riga, Latvia tourist guidebooks, 1975-1976 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1975, 1979, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Clippings about the medical profession, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - College of William and Mary visit, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1978, undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Acrostic puzzles, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1980, 1992, 1996; 1992-1996 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Facts About Germany, ed. Karl Römer, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Mexico travel ephemera, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Mexico travel notes, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Clippings and notes, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 1982-1999 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - University of Heidelberg 600th anniversary and Humboldt Foundation Award, 1984-1986 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Clippings and notes, 1984, 1992-1997; 1992-1997 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - New York Times clippings, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - American Scientist vol. 75 no. 2, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - RSVP forms for Larry Spruch's 70th birthday party (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Notes for speech at 70th birthday party, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - New York Times article on Casimir forces, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Cambridge University Press, Princeton University Press, and Imperial College Press catalogs, 2001-2002 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Rush Holt Congressional campaign, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Notes on music, undated (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Notes on comedy, undated (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Notes on the history of economic thought, undated (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Day planner from a trip to Europe, undated (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Postcards from University of Colorado and Hampton Court Palace, undated (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - List of political "Little-Known Facts" from The Nation, undated (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Harvard ID card and ephemera, undated (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Notes and clippings on economics, undated (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - News clippings and notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Maps of Germany, undated (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Office files, undated (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - Playbills and clippings, undated (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - Notes on the history of experimentation in universities, undated (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - Clippings and notes (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Hotel Slavija stationery, undated (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - Bitnet login instructions, undated (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - European travel ephemera, undated (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - Maps, various locations, undated (Box 37, Folder 51)
- Series VIII: Sports Puzzles, 1965-1996; 1972-1996
  Series VIII contains materials related to another of Larry Spruch's hobbies, writing puzzles. A copy of 21 Astounding Science Quizzes!, written with his wife, Grace Marmor Spruch, is included in this series. However, the rest of the materials relate to the development of a manuscript of sports-themed puzzles which Spruch continued to expand and refine between 1965 and 1996. The manuscript remains unpublished.
  - Correspondence on publication of sports problems, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Hockey problems, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Mountain climbing problems, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "'Hot Dog' Andy": skiing problem, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Volleyball problems, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Swimming problems, 1972, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Outlines for completed sports problems, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Baseball problems, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Football problems, 1972, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Basketball problems, 1972, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - "Bobby Toogud and Boris Gudenuf": Chess problem, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Sports problems manuscript introduction, preface, and "odds and ends", 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Track and Field problems, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - "Is There a 'Best' Team?": Basketball problem, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Bowling problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Golf problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Golf problems (carbon copies), 1975 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Possible problems on horse racing, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Essay problem on the Invention of an Ideal Sport, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Olympic Games problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Notes for "The Next Record to Fall": record-breaking prediction problem, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Sports problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Notes on sports problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Tennis problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Notes on problems to be written, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Outlines of sports problems, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Notes on sports problems manuscript, 1975-1976 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Possible Sports Problems, 1975-1977 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Sports problems, 1975-1990 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Problems submitted to Harper & Row, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Notes and correspondence on publication of sports problems, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence on publication of sports problems, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Sports problems sent to Hugh Rawson at Thomas Y. Crowell Co., 1976 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Problems submitted to Reader's Digest, 1976-1977 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Notes and correspondence on publication of sports problems, 1976, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Notes on possible publishers for sports problems, 1976, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - Notes on "Strange But Interesting Problems", 1977 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - Sports problems, 1979, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - Baseball problems, 1980, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - Baseball problems with tables, with outlines, 1980-1992 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - 21 Astounding Science Quizzes!, Grace Marmor Spruch and Larry Spruch, 1982, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - Sports problem introductions, 1983-1984 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - Baseball problems, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - Baseball problems with outlines, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - Baseball problems with outlines on earned run averages, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - Baseball problems with outlines on geography and history, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - Series of baseball problems about Jack, with outlines, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 47)
  - Baseball problems with outlines on line-ups, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 48)
  - Baseball problems in the series "Somewhat Surprising Questions," with outlines, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 49)
  - Baseball problems in the series "The Most, the Least...," with outlines, 1983, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 50)
  - Baseball problems, 1983-1984, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 51)
  - Baseball problems in the series "Reconstructions," with outlines, 1983-1984, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 52)
  - Baseball problems, 1983-1992 (Box 38, Folder 53)
  - Baseball problems with outlines, 1983-1992 (Box 38, Folder 54)
  - Baseball problems with outlines in the series "Put-outs", 1983-1992 (Box 38, Folder 55)
  - Baseball problems on stolen bases, with outlines, 1983, 1988, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 56)
  - Baseball problems in the series "What Transpired?," with outlines, 1983, 1988, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 57)
  - Sports problems in the series "Potpourri," with outlines, 1983, 1988, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 58)
  - Baseball problems with outlines, 1983-1994 (Box 38, Folder 59)
  - Baseball problems, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 60)
  - Baseball news clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 38, Folder 61)
  - Baseball problems, 1989-1992 (Box 38, Folder 62)
  - Baseball problems, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 63)
  - Baseball problems, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 64)
  - List of potential problems, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 65)
  - Baseball problems, 1992-1994 (Box 38, Folder 66)
  - Babe Herman problem, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 67)
  - Baseball problems, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 68)
  - "Two in One": Sammy Sosa baseball problem, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 69)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Mathematical baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Basketball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Notes on "Betting on the Horses" problem, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Bowling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - "Bobby Toogud and Boris Gudenuf": Chess problem, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Cross country problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Football problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Mathematical football problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Golf problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Hockey problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Sports problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Mountain climbing problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - "'Hot Dog' Andy": mathematical skiing problem, undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Swimming problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Tennis problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Track and Field problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - "Sir Lancelot and Sir Lancelittle": weight lifting problem, undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Wrestling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Sports problems complete manuscript, undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Sports problems manuscript preface, undated (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Sports problems manuscript table of contents, undated (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Selected sports problems from manuscript with Spruch's comments, undated (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Sports problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Complete Sport Problems manuscript submitted to Scribner, undated (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Baseball problems on stolen bases, undated (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Baseball problems with tables, undated (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Baseball problems in the series "What Transpired?", undated (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Baseball problems in the series "Put-Outs", undated (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Baseball problems in the series "Reconstructions", undated (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Baseball problems in the series "Somewhat Surprising Questions", undated (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Sports problems sent to Joe Keller, undated (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Sports problems in the series "Potpourri", undated (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Series of baseball problems about Jack, undated (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Baseball problems on line-ups, undated (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Baseball problems in the series "The Most, the Least...", undated (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Introductory material for specific problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - List of titles of baseball problems; list of "Choice" problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 40)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 41)
  - Mathematical baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 42)
  - "$12 for a $20 Brooch": problem from "Betting on the Horses", undated (Box 39, Folder 43)
  - Cross country problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 44)
  - Mathematical football problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 45)
  - "The Next Record to Fall": record-breaking prediction problem, undated (Box 39, Folder 46)
  - "Sir Lancelot and Sir Lancelittle": weight lifting problem, undated (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Wrestling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 48)
  - Basketball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 49)
  - Tennis problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 50)
  - Football problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 51)
  - Bowling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 52)
  - Golf problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 53)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 54)
  - Bowling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 55)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 56)
  - Sports problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 57)
  - Wrestling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 58)
  - Track and field problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 59)
  - Cross country problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 60)
  - Weight lifting problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 61)
  - "$12 for a $20 Brooch": horse racing problem (draft), undated (Box 39, Folder 62)
  - "The Next Record to Fall": record-breaking prediction problem (draft), undated (Box 39, Folder 63)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 64)
  - Wrestling problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 65)
  - Track and Field problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 66)
  - Cross country problems, undated (Box 39, Folder 67)
  - Bowling problems, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Golf problems, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Football problems, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Baseball problems on batting averages, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Baseball problems on earned run averages, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Baseball problems on geography and history, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Sports problems complete manuscript (another copy), undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Baseball problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Basketball problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Bowling problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Cross country problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Football problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - "$12 for a $20 Brooch": horse racing problem (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - "The Next Record to Fall": record-breaking prediction problem (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Tennis problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Track and field problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Weight lifting problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Wrestling problems (carbon copies), undated (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Cross country problems, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Olympic Games problems, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Volleyball problems, undated (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Baseball problems with outlines, 1983, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Baseball problems on batting averages, undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Baseball problems with outlines, 1983, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Baseball problems, undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Baseball problems with outlines in the series "Put-outs", 1983-1992 (Box 41, Folder 36)